Guide to the Printed Leaves Collection, 1475-1905
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Printed Leaves Collection
1475-1905
0.4 cubic feet (2 boxes)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
An artificial collection of printed leaves, including leaves separated from incunabula as well as later works.
Scope and Content Note
An artificial collection of printed leaves, including leaves separated from incunabula as well as later works.
Access
This collection is open for research according to the regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library without any additional restrictions.
Related Materials
Francis Fitz Randolph Collection of Incunabula Leaves
Subject Headings
Organizations:
Kelmscott Press
Subjects:
Incunabula--Specimens; Printing--Europe--History; Printing--Specimens
Document Types:
Incunabula
VCL Categories:
Printing and Publishing
Encoding Information
Encoded by Laura Streett, January 2015. Last updated by Emma Gronbeck, June 2025.
Acquisition Information
Gifts and purchases from a variety of sources over a number of years.
Arrangement
Arranged chronologically.
Container List
- Laertius, Diogenes. Lives, Teachings, and Sayings of Famous Philosophers. Venice: Nicolas Jenson, 1475; (Goff D-220) (Folder 2.1)
- Bible. Latin. Vulgate. Venice: Nicolas Jenson, 1476; (Goff B-547) (Folder 1.1)
- Higden, Ranulf. Polycronicon. Westminster: William Caxton, After 1482; (Leaves CCIII, CCCXXII. Goff H-267) (Folder 2.2-3)
- Thuróczy, János. Chronica Hungarorum. Brno: Conrad Stahel and Mathias Preunlein, 1488; (Goff T-360) (Folder 1.2)
- Dante Alighieri. Divina Commedia. Venice: Piero de Piasi, 1491; (Goff D-33) (Folder 1.3)
- Cassiodorus. Expositio Psalmorum. Basel: Johann Amerbach, 1491; (Leaves XCVIII, XXXIIII. Goff C-236) (Folder 1.4-5)
- Schedel, Hartmann. Liber Chronicarum. Latin. Nuremberg: Anton Koberger, 1493; (Leaves CXXVI, CLXXXIX. Goff S-307) (Folder 1.6-7)
- Schedel, Hartmann. Liber Chronicarum. German. Nuremberg: Anton Koberger, 1493; (Leaves VI, XXIX, XLI, LVII-LVIII, LXX, LXXXII. Goff S-309) (Folder 1.8-14)
- Voragine, Jacobus de, Golden Legend. London: Wynken de Worde, [1512?] (Folder 1.15)
- Varronis, Cornucopiae. Venice: Aldus Manutius, 1513 (Folder 1.16)
- German Herbal, Late 15th or early 16th century (Folder 2.4)
- Froissart, Chronicles, 16th century (Folder 1.17)
- Apocrypha. English Bible, [16th-17th century?] (Folder 1.18)
- Mamusse Wunneetupanatamwe Up-Biblum God… (Eliot Indian Bible). Cambridge, MA: Samuel Green, 1685 (Folder 1.19)
- Bauhin, Gaspad, Theatri Botanici Sive Historiae Plantarum… Basel, 1685 (Folder 1.2)
- Votes of the Assembly. Philadelphia: Benjamin Franklin, 1753 (Folder 1.21)
- The Holy Bible. Cambridge: John Baskerville, 1763 (Folder 1.22)
- St. Jerome, Vitas Patrum (translated by William Caxton). Hammersmith: Kelmscott Press, 1892; (Trial sheet and Prospectus) (Folder 2.5)
- Voragine, Jacobus de, Golden Legend (translated by William Caxton). Hammersmith: Kelmscott Press, 1892; (Leaves 3-4, 13-14, 295-296, 367-368, 499-500, 523-524) (Folder 2.6)
- The English Bible. Hammersmith: Doves Press, 1903-1905; (1 leaf and 2 bifolia: 19-20, 145-146, 159-160, 261-262, 267-268) (Folder 1.23-25)